Maturity payout is one of the most
significant milestones in an insurance
policy life cycle. At ICICI Credential,
with the help of maturity settlement
option, you have the freedom to shape
your maturity payouts according to your
financial goals. But first, let's
understand what is maturity settlement
option. Maturity settlement option is a
feature in your policy that helps you
receive your maturity payout as per your
financial requirements and lets you
divide your maturity benefits monthly,
quarterly, halfearly or annually. While
you receive these payouts, the remaining
amount stays invested in your policy for
up to 5 years with the potential to
grow. Benefits of opting for maturity
settlement option. One, hasslefree
process. Activate it by logging into our
mobile app or visiting our website. Two,
peace of mind. Decide how and when to
receive your payouts. Three, tax
benefits. Save under section ATC and
ATD. Now, let's understand how to
activate the maturity settlement option.
Log to your ICICI credential account on
our
website using your credentials.
Go to my policies and select the policy
you want to update. Go under the others
section and choose the settlement
option. Choose the duration of the
installments 2 3 4 or 5 years. Select
your preferred payout frequency monthly,
quarterly, half yearly or
annually. Once you're sure, click on the
submit button and a pop-up will appear.
Read the disclaimer carefully and click
on okay. You can also activate the
maturity settlement option on our mobile
app. Login with your login ID and
password and select the policy for which
you like to opt for maturity settlement
option. Choose the installment payout
and click on
submit. Whether you want a steady income
for today or continued growth for the
future. This option helps you with
better financial planning while giving
you peace of mind. For more information,
talk to our adviser today or reach out
to us at
1800260 or email us at
lifelineiciprolive.com or through any of
our touch points for any query or
assistance.